[
    {
        "question": "What is the primary purpose of a sequence in Oracle?",
        "options": [
            "To Create the table to store data",
            "Database object generates unique numeric values automatically",
            "To create views",
            "To perform joins"
        ],
        "answer": "Database object generates unique numeric values automatically"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which option defines the first number generated by a sequence?",
        "options": [
            "INCREMENT BY",
            "START WITH",
            "MINVALUE",
            "MAXVALUE"
        ],
        "answer": "START WITH"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which option controls how much the sequence increases or decreases each time?",
        "options": [
            "INCREMENT BY",
            "START WITH",
            "DECREMENT BY",
            "BIDIRECTION"
        ],
        "answer": "INCREMENT BY"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the NOCYCLE option do?",
        "options": [
            "Stops sequence after reaching MAXVALUE",
            "Restarts sequence after reaching MAXVALUE",
            "Makes sequence decrement",
            "Sets minimum value"
        ],
        "answer": "Stops sequence after reaching MAXVALUE"
    },
    {
        "question": "If a sequence has CYCLE, which of the following is true?",
        "options": [
            "Sequence will stop at MAXVALUE",
            "Sequence will restart from MINVALUE after MAXVALUE",
            "Sequence will always decrement",
            "Sequence cannot be used in INSERT statements"
        ],
        "answer": "Sequence will restart from MINVALUE after MAXVALUE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which clause is used to preallocate sequence numbers in memory for better performance?",
        "options": [
            "NOCYCLE",
            "CACHE",
            "CYCLE",
            "CURRVAL"
        ],
        "answer": "CACHE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which sequence function returns the next value?",
        "options": [
            "CURRVAL",
            "NEXTVAL",
            "INCREMENT",
            "STARTVAL"
        ],
        "answer": "NEXTVAL"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which clause restarts a sequence after reaching its maximum value?",
        "options": [
            "NOCYCLE",
            "CACHE",
            "CYCLE",
            "INCREMENT"
        ],
        "answer": "CYCLE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Is it safe to use a CYCLE sequence for a primary key column?",
        "options": [
            "Yes",
            "No"
        ],
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the default starting value if START WITH is not specified?",
        "options": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "MAXVALUE",
            "MINVALUE"
        ],
        "answer": "1"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the default cache size for a sequence?",
        "options": [
            "5",
            "10",
            "20",
            "50"
        ],
        "answer": "20"
    },
    {
        "question": "What happens if CURRVAL is used before NEXTVAL?",
        "options": [
            "Returns NULL",
            "Returns 0",
            "Generates next value",
            "ORA-08002 error"
        ],
        "answer": "ORA-08002 error"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does happens when we create the sequence NOCACHE?",
        "options": [
            "Stores values permanently",
            "Generates values one by one",
            "Improves speed",
            "Enables cycling"
        ],
        "answer": "Generates values one by one"
    },
    {
        "question": "Default sequence behavior is?",
        "options": [
            "CYCLE",
            "NOCYCLE",
            "CACHE 5",
            "NOCACHE"
        ],
        "answer": "NOCYCLE"
    },
    {
        "question": "Do sequences guarantee gap-free numbers?",
        "options": [
            "Yes",
            "No"
        ],
        "answer": "No"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which option CANNOT be altered?",
        "options": [
            "INCREMENT BY",
            "CACHE",
            "MAXVALUE",
            "START WITH",
            "MINVALUE"
        ],
        "answer": "START WITH"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT true about an Oracle Sequence?",
        "options": [
            "A single sequence can be used by only one table",
            "A sequence can be used for multiple tables",
            "If we drop a table, the sequence will not be dropped",
            "A sequence is an independent database object"
        ],
        "answer": "A single sequence can be used by only one table"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the purpose of CURRVAL in a sequence?",
        "options": [
            "Generates the next sequence number",
            "Returns the current value of the sequence in the session",
            "Resets the sequence",
            "CURRVAL can be used before NEXTVAL"
        ],
        "answer": "Returns the current value of the sequence in the session"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which SQL statement correctly retrieves the current value of a sequence?",
        "options": [
            "SELECT emp_seq.VALUE FROM dual;",
            "SELECT emp_seq.CURRVAL FROM dual;",
            "SELECT CURRVAL(emp_seq) FROM dual;",
            "SELECT CURRENT(emp_seq) FROM dual;"
        ],
        "answer": "SELECT emp_seq.CURRVAL FROM dual;"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the correct syntax to create a sequence?",
        "options": [
            "CREATE SEQUENCE emp_seq START 1 INCREMENT 1;",
            "CREATE emp_seq SEQUENCE START WITH 1;",
            "CREATE SEQUENCE emp_seq START WITH 1 INCREMENT BY 1;",
            "CREATE emp_seq START WITH 1"
        ],
        "answer": "CREATE SEQUENCE emp_seq START WITH 1 INCREMENT BY 1;"
    }
]